<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Todd Constable</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Todd Constable</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustworthy ML &amp; Robust Statistics</title>
      <link>/research/trust.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/trust.md/</guid>
      <description>As machine learning systems are pervasively deployed in many scientific fields with increasingly sensitive tasks, it has become paramount to develop algorithms that are robust against the numerous sources of uncertainty inherent in those applications including noise in the data, malicious exploitation of vulnerabilities, outliers, variability of the true objective, privacy, and fairness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task-induced brain state manipulation</title>
      <link>/posts/abigail-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/abigail-18/</guid>
      <description>Recent work has begun to relate individual differences in brain functional organization to human behaviors and cognition, but the best brain state to reveal such relationships remains an open question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Transport and Brain Imaging</title>
      <link>/posts/ot-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ot-2021/</guid>
      <description>Fuctional connectomes, derived from functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) is widely used to study functional organization of human brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hitchhiker’s guide to working with large, open-source neuroimaging datasets</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/nhb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/nhb-2021/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Large datasets that enable researchers to perform investigations with unprecedented rigor are growing increasingly common in neuroimaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transdiagnostic, Connectome-Based Prediction of Memory Constructs Across Psychiatric Disorders</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/ccortex-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/ccortex-2021/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Memory deficits are observed in a range of psychiatric disorders, but it is unclear whether memory deficits arise from a shared brain correlate across disorders or from various dysfunctions unique to each disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Within node connectivity changes, not simply edge changes, influence graph theory measures in functional connectivity studies of the brain</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/neuroimage-luou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/neuroimage-luou/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Interest in understanding the organization of the brain has led to the application of graph theory methods across a wide array of functional connectivity studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Neuroscience</title>
      <link>/research/computational_neuroscience_neurimaging.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/computational_neuroscience_neurimaging.md/</guid>
      <description>The human brain is a complex network, consisting of functionally interconnected regions whose coordinated effort gives rise to different functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-convex Optimization</title>
      <link>/research/non_convex.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/non_convex.md/</guid>
      <description>Until recently, convex programs were seen as the defining boundary for tractability in continuous optimization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Learning</title>
      <link>/research/online_learning.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/online_learning.md/</guid>
      <description>In many practical applications, the environment is so complex that it may be infeasible to lay out a precise model and use the classical mathematical optimization methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submodular Optimization</title>
      <link>/research/submodular_optimization.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/submodular_optimization.md/</guid>
      <description>The difficulty of searching through a massive amount of data in order to quickly make an informed decision is one of today’s most ubiquitous challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Decision Making</title>
      <link>/research/interactive_decision_making.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/interactive_decision_making.md/</guid>
      <description>In computer science, and machine learning in particular, the primary purpose of many systems is to help humans make decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Todd Constable&amp;rsquo;s research primarily focuses on functional magnetic resonance (MR) and understanding cognitive processes that are related to language and memory and how these processes may be altered in different disease states or with different medications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>