<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Todd Constable</title>
    <link>/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Todd Constable</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining Multiple Behavioral Measures and Multiple Connectomes via Multipath Canonical Correlation Analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/2019/miccai-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019/miccai-2019/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional connectomes can successfully predict behavioral measures. While the majority of the literature uses a single connectome to predict a single behavioral measure, there is ample evidence that combining different connectomes and behavioral measures reveals more robust neural correlates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Graph Theory-based Whole Brain Approach to Assess Mood State Differences in Adolescents and Young Adults with Bipolar Disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-10-19_bipolar-disord_157/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-10-19_bipolar-disord_157/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVES: Identifying hubs of brain dysfunction in adolescents and young adults with Bipolar I Disorder (BDAYA ) could provide targets for early detection, prevention and treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic variation in endocannabinoid signaling is associated with differential network-level functional connectivity in youth</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-09-08_j-neurosci-res_140/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-09-08_j-neurosci-res_140/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Cocaine-dependent individuals demonstrate neural and behavioral differences compared to healthy comparison subjects when performing the Stroop color-word interference test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Connectivity during Encoding Predicts Individual Differences in Long-Term Memory</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-07-17_j-cogn-neurosci_87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-07-17_j-cogn-neurosci_87/</guid>
      <description>Abstract What is the neural basis of individual differences in the ability to hold information in long-term memory (LTM)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Within node connectivity changes, not simply edge changes, influence graph theory measures in functional connectivity studies of the brain</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-07-05_neuroimage_186/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-07-05_neuroimage_186/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Interest in understanding the organization of the brain has led to the application of graph theory methods across a wide array of functional connectivity studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hitchhiker’s guide to working with large, open-source neuroimaging datasets</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/nhb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/nhb-2021/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Large datasets that enable researchers to perform investigations with unprecedented rigor are growing increasingly common in neuroimaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transdiagnostic, Connectome-Based Prediction of Memory Constructs Across Psychiatric Disorders</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/ccortex-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/ccortex-2021/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Memory deficits are observed in a range of psychiatric disorders, but it is unclear whether memory deficits arise from a shared brain correlate across disorders or from various dysfunctions unique to each disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Within node connectivity changes, not simply edge changes, influence graph theory measures in functional connectivity studies of the brain</title>
      <link>/publications/2021/neuroimage-luou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021/neuroimage-luou/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Interest in understanding the organization of the brain has led to the application of graph theory methods across a wide array of functional connectivity studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Author Correction: Simultaneous cortex-wide fluorescence Ca(2&#43;) imaging and whole-brain fMRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-06-24_nat-methods_111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-06-24_nat-methods_111/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using functional connectivity models to characterize relationships between working and episodic memory</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-06-18_brain-behav_88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-06-18_brain-behav_88/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Blood glucose levels influence brain regulation of food intake. This study assessed the effect of mild physiological hyperglycemia on brain response to food cues in individuals with obesity (OB) versus normal weight individuals (NW).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainhack: Developing a culture of open, inclusive, community-driven neuroscience</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-05-01_neuron_78/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-05-01_neuron_78/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Collaborators: Anousheh N, Arnatkeviciute A, Auzias G, Bachar D, Bannier E, Basanisi R, Basavaraj A, Bedini M, Bellec P, Benn RA, Berluti K, Bollmann S, Bollmann S, Bradley C, Brown J, Buchweitz A, Callahan P, Chan MY, Chandio BQ, Cheng T, Chopra S, Chung AW, Close TG, Combrisson E, Cona G, Constable RT, Cury C, Dadi K, Damasceno PF, Das S, De Vico Fallani F, DeStasio K, Dickie EW, Dorfschmidt L, Duff EP, DuPre E, Dziura S, Esper NB, Esteban O, Fadnavis S, Flandin G, Flannery JE, Flournoy J, Forkel SJ, Franco AR, Ganesan S, Gao S, García Alanis JC, Garyfallidis E, Glatard T, Glerean E, Gonzalez-Castillo J, Gould van Praag CD, Greene AS, Gupta G, Hahn CA, Halchenko YO, Handwerker D, Hartmann TS, Hayot-Sasson V, Heunis S, Hoffstaedter F, Hohmann DM, Horien C, Ioanas HI, Iordan A, Jiang C, Joseph M, Kai J, Karakuzu A, Kennedy DN, Keshavan A, Khan AR, Kiar G, Klink PC, Koppelmans V, Koudoro S, Laird AR, Langs G, Laws M, Licandro R, Liew SL, Lipic T, Litinas K, Lurie DJ, Lussier D, Madan CR, Mais LT, Mansour L S, Manzano-Patron JP, Maoutsa D, Marcon M, Margulies DS, Marinato G, Marinazzo D, Markiewicz CJ, Maumet C, Meneguzzi F, Meunier D, Milham MP, Mills KL, Momi D, Moreau CA, Motala A, Moxon-Emre I, Nichols TE, Nielson DM, Nilsonne G, Novello L, O&amp;rsquo;Brien C, Olafson E, Oliver LD, Onofrey JA, Orchard ER, Oudyk K, Park PJ, Parsapoor M, Pasquini L, Peltier S, Pernet CR, Pienaar R, Pinheiro-Chagas P, Poline JB, Qiu A, Quendera T, Rice LC, Rocha-Hidalgo J, Rutherford S, Scharinger M, Scheinost D, Shariq D, Shaw TB, Siless V, Simmonite M, Sirmpilatze N, Spence H, Sprenger J, Stajduhar A, Szinte M, Takerkart S, Tam A, Tejavibulya L, Thiebaut de Schotten M, Thome I, Tomaz da Silva L, Traut N, Uddin LQ, Vallesi A, VanMeter JW, Vijayakumar N, di Oleggio Castello MV, Vohryzek J, Vukojević J, Whitaker KJ, Whitmore L, Wideman S, Witt ST, Xie H, Xu T, Yan CG, Yeh FC, Yeo BTT, Zuo XN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging and Reimagining the Mind: fMRI and Psychiatric Illness</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-04-16_biol-psychiatry_59/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-04-16_biol-psychiatry_59/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resample aggregating improves the generalizability of connectome predictive modeling</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-04-13_neuroimage_62/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-04-13_neuroimage_62/</guid>
      <description>Abstract It is a longstanding goal of neuroimaging to produce reliable, generalizable models of brain behavior relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence Between Perceived Pubertal Development and Hormone Levels in 9-10 Year-Olds From the Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development Study</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-03-08_front-endocrinol-lausanne_153/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-03-08_front-endocrinol-lausanne_153/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to the measurement and interpretation of fMRI test-retest reliability</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-02-15_curr-opin-behav-sci_73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-02-15_curr-opin-behav-sci_73/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The test-retest reliability of functional neuroimaging data has recently been a topic of much discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Network Development in Sagittal Craniosynostosis Treated With Whole Vault Cranioplasty</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-02-03_j-craniofac-surg_93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-02-03_j-craniofac-surg_93/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transdiagnostic, Connectome-Based Prediction of Memory Constructs Across Psychiatric Disorders</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-12-21_cereb-cortex_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-12-21_cereb-cortex_28/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Memory deficits are observed in a range of psychiatric disorders, but it is unclear whether memory deficits arise from a shared brain correlate across disorders or from various dysfunctions unique to each disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain anatomical covariation patterns linked to binge drinking and age at first full drink</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-12-15_neuroimage-clin_57/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-12-15_neuroimage-clin_57/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Conflict of interest statement: Dr. Potenza has the following disclosures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-motion fMRI data can be obtained in pediatric participants undergoing a 60-minute scan protocol</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-12-15_sci-rep_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-12-15_sci-rep_22/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Performing functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) scans of children can be a difficult task, as participants tend to move while being scanned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to Behavioral and brain signatures of substance use vulnerability in childhood [Developmental Cognitive Neuroscience 46 (December) (2020) 100878]</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-12-14_dev-cogn-neurosci_81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-12-14_dev-cogn-neurosci_81/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hitchhiker&#39;s guide to working with large, open-source neuroimaging datasets</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-12-08_nat-hum-behav_33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-12-08_nat-hum-behav_33/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Large datasets that enable researchers to perform investigations with unprecedented rigor are growing increasingly common in neuroimaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural and functional brain changes in hepatic and neurological Wilson disease</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-11-27_brain-imaging-behav_41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-11-27_brain-imaging-behav_41/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Wilson disease (WD) can manifest with hepatic or neuropsychiatric symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral and brain signatures of substance use vulnerability in childhood</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-11-12_dev-cogn-neurosci_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-11-12_dev-cogn-neurosci_12/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The prevalence of risky behavior such as substance use increases during adolescence; however, the neurobiological precursors to adolescent substance use remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous cortex-wide fluorescence Ca(2&#43;) imaging and whole-brain fMRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-11-03_nat-methods_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-11-03_nat-methods_5/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Achieving a comprehensive understanding of brain function requires multiple imaging modalities with complementary strengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tasks Change Whole-Brain Functional Organization to Reveal Brain-Phenotype Relationships</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-08-27_cell-rep_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-08-27_cell-rep_11/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional connectivity (FC) calculated from task fMRI data better reveals brain-phenotype relationships than rest-based FC, but how tasks have this effect is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connectome-based models can predict early symptom improvement in major depressive disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-06-21_j-affect-disord_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-06-21_j-affect-disord_21/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Major depressive disorder (MDD) is a debilitating mental illness with more than 50% of patients not achieving an adequate response using first-line treatments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered frontal cortex functioning in emotion regulation and hopelessness in bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-06-11_bipolar-disord_56/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-06-11_bipolar-disord_56/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVES: Emotion regulation difficulties precipitate and exacerbate acute mood symptoms in individuals with bipolar disorder (BD), and contribute to suicidal behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hippocampal seed connectome-based modeling predicts the feeling of stress</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-05-29_nat-commun_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-05-29_nat-commun_6/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Although the feeling of stress is ubiquitous, the neural mechanisms underlying this affective experience remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of a brain fingerprint for overweight and obesity</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-05-18_physiol-behav_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-05-18_physiol-behav_7/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The brain plays a central role in the pathophysiology of overweight and obesity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loss of nucleus accumbens low-frequency fluctuations is a signature of chronic pain</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-04-22_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-04-22_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_19/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connectome-based neurofeedback: A pilot study to improve sustained attention</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-03-02_neuroimage_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-03-02_neuroimage_8/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Real-time functional magnetic resonance imaging (rt-fMRI) neurofeedback is a non-invasive, non-pharmacological therapeutic tool that may be useful for training behavior and alleviating clinical symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity predicts changes in attention observed across minutes, days, and months</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-02-06_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-02-06_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_16/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster failure or power failure? Evaluating sensitivity in cluster-level inference</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-12-20_neuroimage_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-12-20_neuroimage_15/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The ability to sustain attention differs across people and changes within a single person over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is no single functional atlas even for a single individual: Functional parcel definitions change with task</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-11-20_neuroimage_31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-11-20_neuroimage_31/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The goal of human brain mapping has long been to delineate the functional subunits in the brain and elucidate the functional role of each of these brain regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular pH mapping of liver cancer on a clinical 3T MRI scanner</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-11-07_magn-reson-med_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-11-07_magn-reson-med_20/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: To demonstrate feasibility of developing a noninvasive extracellular pH (pHe ) mapping method on a clinical MRI scanner for molecular imaging of liver cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous mesoscopic and two-photon imaging of neuronal activity in cortical circuits</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-11-06_nat-methods_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-11-06_nat-methods_1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Spontaneous and sensory-evoked activity propagates across varying spatial scales in the mammalian cortex, but technical challenges have limited conceptual links between the function of local neuronal circuits and brain-wide network dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Patterns of Functional Connectivity Predict Working Memory Performance in Novel Healthy and Memory-impaired Individuals</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-10-30_j-cogn-neurosci_29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-10-30_j-cogn-neurosci_29/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Individual differences in working memory relate to performance differences in general cognitive ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individualized functional networks reconfigure with cognitive state</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-10-02_neuroimage_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-10-02_neuroimage_4/</guid>
      <description>Abstract There is extensive evidence that functional organization of the human brain varies dynamically as the brain switches between task demands, or cognitive states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Resting State Connectivity Responses to Glycemic State in Type 1 Diabetes</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-09-13_j-clin-endocrinol-metab_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-09-13_j-clin-endocrinol-metab_18/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Chronic pain is a highly prevalent disease with poorly understood pathophysiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade of test-retest reliability of functional connectivity: A systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-09-09_neuroimage_50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-09-09_neuroimage_50/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Once considered mere noise, fMRI-based functional connectivity has become a major neuroscience tool in part due to early studies demonstrating its reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image processing and analysis methods for the Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development Study</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-08-16_neuroimage_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-08-16_neuroimage_0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development (ABCD) Study is an ongoing, nationwide study of the effects of environmental influences on behavioral and brain development in adolescents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining multiple connectomes improves predictive modeling of phenotypic measures</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-07-24_neuroimage_35/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-07-24_neuroimage_35/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Resting-state and task-based functional connectivity matrices, or connectomes, are powerful predictors of individual differences in phenotypic measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regions and Connections: Complementary Approaches to Characterize Brain Organization and Function</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-07-16_neuroscientist_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-07-16_neuroscientist_10/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional magnetic resonance imaging has proved to be a powerful tool to characterize spatiotemporal patterns of human brain activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An information network flow approach for measuring functional connectivity and predicting behavior</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-07-10_brain-behav_47/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-07-10_brain-behav_47/</guid>
      <description>Abstract INTRODUCTION: Connectome-based predictive modeling (CPM) is a recently developed machine-learning-based framework to predict individual differences in behavior from functional brain connectivity (FC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate approaches improve the reliability and validity of functional connectivity and prediction of individual behaviors</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-05-01_neuroimage_64/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-05-01_neuroimage_64/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Brain functional connectivity features can predict cognition and behavior at the level of the individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic-flip-angle ECG-gating with nuisance signal regression improves resting-state BOLD functional connectivity mapping by reducing cardiogenic noise</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-04-25_magn-reson-med_74/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-04-25_magn-reson-med_74/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: To investigate an ECG-gated dynamic-flip-angle BOLD sequence with improved robustness against cardiogenic noise in resting-state fMRI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Functional Brain Organization of an Individual Allows Prediction of Measures of Social Abilities Transdiagnostically in Autism and Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-04-24_biol-psychiatry_83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-04-24_biol-psychiatry_83/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Autism spectrum disorder and attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) are associated with complex changes as revealed by functional magnetic resonance imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Functional Difference Between Sagittal With Metopic and Isolated Sagittal Craniosynotosis?</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-03-19_j-craniofac-surg_44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-03-19_j-craniofac-surg_44/</guid>
      <description>Abstract INTRODUCTION: The purpose of this study is to understand the neurological differences between patients born with combined sagittal and metopic craniosynostosis (SMc) and isolated sagittal craniosynostosis (ISc) by studying aberrations in functional brain connectivity and white matter microstructure, before surgery, utilizing functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and diffusion tensor imaging (DTI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten simple rules for predictive modeling of individual differences in neuroimaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-03-05_neuroimage_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-03-05_neuroimage_14/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Establishing brain-behavior associations that map brain organization to phenotypic measures and generalize to novel individuals remains a challenge in neuroimaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Potential of a New Approach to MRI Acceleration</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-02-15_sci-rep_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-02-15_sci-rep_23/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fast ROtary Nonlinear Spatial ACquisition (FRONSAC) was recently introduced as a new strategy that applies nonlinear gradients as a small perturbation to improve image quality in highly undersampled MRI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The individual functional connectome is unique and stable over months to years</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-02-06_neuroimage_43/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-02-06_neuroimage_43/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional connectomes computed from fMRI provide a means to characterize individual differences in the patterns of BOLD synchronization across regions of the entire brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Learning Disabilities Linked to Sagittal Craniosynostosis</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-01-25_j-craniofac-surg_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-01-25_j-craniofac-surg_25/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study is to investigate further findings that corroborate similarities between corrected sagittal craniosynostosis and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite reliability and repeatability of an advanced brain MRI protocol</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-01-18_j-magn-reson-imaging_37/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-01-18_j-magn-reson-imaging_37/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: MRI is the imaging modality of choice for diagnosis and intervention assessment in neurological disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insula as the Interface Between Body Awareness and Movement: A Neurofeedback-Guided Kinesthetic Motor Imagery Study in Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-12-25_front-hum-neurosci_137/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-12-25_front-hum-neurosci_137/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Intentional movement is an internally driven process that requires the integration of motivational and sensory cues with motor preparedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic functional connectivity during task performance and rest predicts individual differences in attention across studies</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-12-07_neuroimage_58/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-12-07_neuroimage_58/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Dynamic functional connectivity (DFC) aims to maximize resolvable information from functional brain scans by considering temporal changes in network structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the prediction of emotional valence and pharmacologic effect across fMRI studies of antidepressants</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-08-22_neuroimage-clin_92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-08-22_neuroimage-clin_92/</guid>
      <description>Abstract INTRODUCTION: In this study, the authors seek to clarify the neurological changes before and after whole vault cranioplasty (WVC) in patients born with sagittal craniosynostosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task-induced brain state manipulation improves prediction of individual traits</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-07-20_nat-commun_46/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-07-20_nat-commun_46/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent work has begun to relate individual differences in brain functional organization to human behaviors and cognition, but the best brain state to reveal such relationships remains an open question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trait paranoia shapes inter-subject synchrony in brain activity during an ambiguous social narrative</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-05-26_nat-commun_85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-05-26_nat-commun_85/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Individuals often interpret the same event in different ways. How do personality traits modulate brain activity evoked by a complex stimulus?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-Driven Analysis of Functional Connectivity Reveals a Potential Auditory Verbal Hallucination Network</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-04-17_schizophr-bull_48/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-04-17_schizophr-bull_48/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The effect of life stress on depression is moderated by a repeat length variation in the transcriptional control region of the serotonin transporter gene, which renders carriers of the short variant vulnerable for depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presurgical language fMRI: Clinical practices and patient outcomes in epilepsy surgical planning</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-03-13_hum-brain-mapp_91/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-03-13_hum-brain-mapp_91/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The goal of this study was to document current clinical practice and report patient outcomes in presurgical language functional MRI (fMRI) for epilepsy surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans with obesity have disordered brain responses to food images during physiological hyperglycemia</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-01-31_am-j-physiol-endocrinol-metab_89/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-01-31_am-j-physiol-endocrinol-metab_89/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoglycemia unawareness in type 1 diabetes suppresses brain responses to hypoglycemia</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-01-31_j-clin-invest_82/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-01-31_j-clin-invest_82/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Among nondiabetic individuals, mild glucose decrements alter brain activity in regions linked to reward, motivation, and executive control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resting-state functional connectivity predicts neuroticism and extraversion in novel individuals</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-01-27_soc-cogn-affect-neurosci_66/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-01-27_soc-cogn-affect-neurosci_66/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The personality dimensions of neuroticism and extraversion are strongly associated with emotional experience and affective disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering factors affecting the connectome-based identification process: Comment on Waller et al</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-12-19_neuroimage_90/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-12-19_neuroimage_90/</guid>
      <description>Abstract A recent study by Waller and colleagues evaluated the reliability, specificity, and generalizability of using functional connectivity data to identify individuals from a group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connectome-based predictive modeling of attention: Comparing different functional connectivity features and prediction methods across datasets</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-11-11_neuroimage_107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-11-11_neuroimage_107/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Connectome-based predictive modeling (CPM; Finn et al., 2015; Shen et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NAIMS cooperative pilot project: Design, implementation and future directions</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-11-07_mult-scler_79/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-11-07_mult-scler_79/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The North American Imaging in Multiple Sclerosis (NAIMS) Cooperative represents a network of 27 academic centers focused on accelerating the pace of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) research in multiple sclerosis (MS) through idea exchange and collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connectome-based Models Predict Separable Components of Attention in Novel Individuals</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-10-18_j-cogn-neurosci_60/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-10-18_j-cogn-neurosci_60/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Active coping underlies a healthy stress response, but neural processes supporting such resilient coping are not well-known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences on the Test-Retest Reliability of Functional Connectivity MRI and its Relationship with Behavioral Utility</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-10-03_cereb-cortex_94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-10-03_cereb-cortex_94/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Best practices are currently being developed for the acquisition and processing of resting-state magnetic resonance imaging data used to estimate brain functional organization-or &amp;ldquo;functional connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered functional connectivity to stressful stimuli in prenatally cocaine-exposed adolescents</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-09-10_drug-alcohol-depend_71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-09-10_drug-alcohol-depend_71/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An exemplar-based approach to individualized parcellation reveals the need for sex specific functional networks</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-09-09_neuroimage_36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-09-09_neuroimage_36/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent work with functional connectivity data has led to significant progress in understanding the functional organization of the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient nonlinearity effects on upper cervical spinal cord area measurement from 3D T(1) -weighted brain MRI acquisitions</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-06-16_magn-reson-med_119/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-06-16_magn-reson-med_119/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to explore the relationship between global brain activity, changes in whole-brain connectivity, and changes in brain states across subjects using resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presurgical language fMRI: Mapping of six critical regions</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-05-26_hum-brain-mapp_51/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-05-26_hum-brain-mapp_51/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Language mapping is a key goal in neurosurgical planning. fMRI mapping typically proceeds with a focus on Broca&amp;rsquo;s and Wernicke&amp;rsquo;s areas, although multiple other language-critical areas are now well-known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can brain state be manipulated to emphasize individual differences in functional connectivity?</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-04-05_neuroimage_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-04-05_neuroimage_24/</guid>
      <description>Abstract While neuroimaging studies typically collapse data from many subjects, brain functional organization varies between individuals, and characterizing this variability is crucial for relating brain activity to behavioral phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared microstructural features of behavioral and substance addictions revealed in areas of crossing fibers</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-04-04_biol-psychiatry-cogn-neurosci-neuroimaging_98/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-04-04_biol-psychiatry-cogn-neurosci-neuroimaging_98/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topographic organization of the cerebral cortex and brain cartography</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-02-22_neuroimage_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-02-22_neuroimage_13/</guid>
      <description>Abstract One of the most specific but also challenging properties of the brain is its topographic organization into distinct modules or cortical areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using connectome-based predictive modeling to predict individual behavior from brain connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-02-10_nat-protoc_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-02-10_nat-protoc_3/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Neuroimaging is a fast-developing research area in which anatomical and functional images of human brains are collected using techniques such as functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), diffusion tensor imaging (DTI), and electroencephalography (EEG).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gray-matter relationships to diagnostic and transdiagnostic features of drug and behavioral addictions</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-02-03_addict-biol_84/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-02-03_addict-biol_84/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Alterations in neural structure have been reported in both cocaine-use disorder and gambling disorder, separately, suggesting similarities across addiction diagnoses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-modal analysis of functional connectivity and cerebral blood flow reveals shared and unique effects of propofol in large-scale brain networks</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-01-11_neuroimage_164/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-01-11_neuroimage_164/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Anesthesia-induced changes in functional connectivity and cerebral blow flow (CBF) in large-scale brain networks have emerged as key markers of reduced consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak functional connectivity in the human fetal brain prior to preterm birth</title>
      <link>/publications/2017-01-10_sci-rep_72/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2017-01-10_sci-rep_72/</guid>
      <description>Abstract It has been suggested that neurological problems more frequent in those born preterm are expressed prior to birth, but owing to technical limitations, this has been difficult to test in humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cingulate cortex functional connectivity predicts future relapse in alcohol dependent individuals</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-12-17_neuroimage-clin_80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-12-17_neuroimage-clin_80/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Alcohol dependence is a chronic relapsing illness. Alcohol and stress cues have consistently been shown to increase craving and relapse risk in recovering alcohol dependent (AUD) patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-space with high resolution readouts outperforms radial imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-11-24_magn-reson-imaging_54/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-11-24_magn-reson-imaging_54/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: While O-Space imaging is well known to accelerate image acquisition beyond traditional Cartesian sampling, its advantages compared to undersampled radial imaging, the linear trajectory most akin to O-Space imaging, have not been detailed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reorganization of brain connectivity in obesity</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-11-19_hum-brain-mapp_30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-11-19_hum-brain-mapp_30/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Global brain connectivity (GBC) identifies regions of the brain, termed &amp;ldquo;hubs,&amp;rdquo; which are densely connected and metabolically costly, and have a wide influence on brain function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired consciousness in patients with absence seizures investigated by functional MRI, EEG, and behavioural measures: a cross-sectional study</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-11-15_lancet-neurol_238/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-11-15_lancet-neurol_238/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The central vein sign and its clinical evaluation for the diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: a consensus statement from the North American Imaging in Multiple Sclerosis Cooperative</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-11-12_nat-rev-neurol_42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-11-12_nat-rev-neurol_42/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Over the past few years, MRI has become an indispensable tool for diagnosing multiple sclerosis (MS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual variation in functional brain connectivity: implications for personalized approaches to psychiatric disease</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-10-21_dialogues-clin-neurosci_27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-10-21_dialogues-clin-neurosci_27/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite reliability of MR-based functional connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-10-18_neuroimage_34/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-10-18_neuroimage_34/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent years have witnessed an increasing number of multisite MRI functional connectivity (fcMRI) studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Localization of Long-Distance Dependency Components: Integrating the Focal-lesion and Neuroimaging Record</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-10-18_front-psychol_109/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-10-18_front-psychol_109/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In the sentence &amp;ldquo;The captain who the sailor greeted is tall,&amp;rdquo; the connection between the relative pronoun and the object position of greeted represents a long-distance dependency (LDD), necessary for the interpretation of &amp;ldquo;the captain&amp;rdquo; as the individual being greeted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does prenatal stress alter the developing connectome?</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-09-28_pediatr-res_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-09-28_pediatr-res_9/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Human neurodevelopment requires the organization of neural elements into complex structural and functional networks called the connectome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methylphenidate Modulates Functional Network Connectivity to Enhance Attention</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-09-16_j-neurosci_63/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-09-16_j-neurosci_63/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent work has demonstrated that human whole-brain functional connectivity patterns measured with fMRI contain information about cognitive abilities, including sustained attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prenatal stress alters amygdala functional connectivity in preterm neonates</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-09-14_neuroimage-clin_69/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-09-14_neuroimage-clin_69/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Exposure to prenatal and early-life stress results in alterations in neural connectivity and an increased risk for neuropsychiatric disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluctuations in Global Brain Activity Are Associated With Changes in Whole-Brain Connectivity of Functional Networks</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-08-20_ieee-trans-biomed-eng_120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-08-20_ieee-trans-biomed-eng_120/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic neural activity during stress signals resilient coping</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-07-20_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_61/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-07-20_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_61/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered Brain Response to Drinking Glucose and Fructose in Obese Adolescents</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-05-22_diabetes_100/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-05-22_diabetes_100/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Increased sugar-sweetened beverage consumption has been linked to higher rates of obesity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional magnetic resonance connectivity studies in infants born preterm: suggestions of proximate and long-lasting changes in language organization</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-03-31_dev-med-child-neurol_39/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-03-31_dev-med-child-neurol_39/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Connectivity During Exposure to Favorite-Food, Stress, and Neutral-Relaxing Imagery Differs Between Smokers and Nonsmokers</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-03-21_nicotine-tob-res_123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-03-21_nicotine-tob-res_123/</guid>
      <description>Abstract INTRODUCTION: Tobacco-use disorder is a complex condition involving multiple brain networks and presenting with multiple behavioral correlates including changes in diet and stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language at rest: A longitudinal study of intrinsic functional connectivity in preterm children</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-03-04_neuroimage-clin_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-03-04_neuroimage-clin_101/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Preterm (PT) children show early cognitive and language deficits and display altered cortical connectivity for language compared to term (T) children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metonymy as Referential Dependency: Psycholinguistic and Neurolinguistic Arguments for a Unified Linguistic Treatment</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-02-19_cogn-sci_95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-02-19_cogn-sci_95/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We examine metonymy at psycho- and neurolinguistic levels, seeking to adjudicate between two possible processing implementations (one- vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion Tensor Imaging in Patients with Glioblastoma Multiforme Using the Supertoroidal Model</title>
      <link>/publications/2016-01-14_plos-one_103/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2016-01-14_plos-one_103/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI) is a powerful imaging technique that has led to improvements in the diagnosis and prognosis of cerebral lesions and neurosurgical guidance for tumor resection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization of brain morphology after surgery in sagittal craniosynostosis</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-12-20_j-neurosurg-pediatr_68/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-12-20_j-neurosurg-pediatr_68/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECT Nonsyndromic craniosynostosis (NSC) is associated with significant learning disability later in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Nonlinear Gradients in Parallel Imaging: A k-Space Based Analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-11-26_concepts-magn-reson-part-a-bridg-educ-res_116/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-11-26_concepts-magn-reson-part-a-bridg-educ-res_116/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A neuromarker of sustained attention from whole-brain functional connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-11-24_nat-neurosci_53/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-11-24_nat-neurosci_53/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Although attention plays a ubiquitous role in perception and cognition, researchers lack a simple way to measure a person&amp;rsquo;s overall attentional abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alterations in Anatomical Covariance in the Prematurely Born</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-10-24_cereb-cortex_45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-10-24_cereb-cortex_45/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Preterm (PT) birth results in long-term alterations in functional and structural connectivity, but the related changes in anatomical covariance are just beginning to be explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectome fingerprinting: identifying individuals using patterns of brain connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-10-13_nat-neurosci_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-10-13_nat-neurosci_2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) studies typically collapse data from many subjects, but brain functional organization varies between individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preterm birth alters neonatal, functional rich club organization</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-09-06_brain-struct-funct_52/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-09-06_brain-struct-funct_52/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Alterations in neural networks are associated with the cognitive difficulties of the prematurely born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (in)stability of functional brain network measures across thresholds</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-05-30_neuroimage_76/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-05-30_neuroimage_76/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The large-scale organization of the brain has features of complex networks that can be quantified using network measures from graph theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental O-space turbo spin echo imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-05-19_magn-reson-med_70/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-05-19_magn-reson-med_70/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Prenatal cocaine exposure (PCE) is linked to addiction and obesity vulnerability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast rotary nonlinear spatial acquisition (FRONSAC) imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-05-08_magn-reson-med_55/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-05-08_magn-reson-med_55/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: Nonlinear spatial encoding magnetic fields (SEMs) have been studied to reconstruct images from a minimum number of echoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditation leads to reduced default mode network activity beyond an active task</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-04-24_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_113/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-04-24_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_113/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of an fMRI paradigm for emotional processing in a multisite longitudinal study</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-03-31_hum-brain-mapp_110/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-03-31_hum-brain-mapp_110/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Multisite neuroimaging studies can facilitate the investigation of brain-related changes in many contexts, including patient groups that are relatively rare in the general population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting moment-to-moment attentional state</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-03-25_neuroimage_32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-03-25_neuroimage_32/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Although fluctuations in sustained attention are ubiquitous, most psychological experiments treat them as noise, averaging performance over many trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Magnetic resonance electrical property tomography based on B1(-) field mapping</title>
      <link>/publications/2015-01-09_annu-int-conf-ieee-eng-med-biol-soc_250/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2015-01-09_annu-int-conf-ieee-eng-med-biol-soc_250/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive mechanisms of developing brain: cerebral lateralization in the prematurely-born</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-12-22_neuroimage_96/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-12-22_neuroimage_96/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Preterm birth results in alterations in neural connectivity, but the impact of prematurity on the functional organization of the developing brain has yet to be explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex differences in normal age trajectories of functional brain networks</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-12-20_hum-brain-mapp_97/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-12-20_hum-brain-mapp_97/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Similarities between behavioral and substance addictions exist. However, direct neurobiological comparison between addictive disorders is rare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered functional connectivity in seizure onset zones revealed by fMRI intrinsic connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-11-14_neurology_124/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-11-14_neurology_124/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to investigate functional connectivity (FC) changes in epileptogenic networks in intractable partial epilepsy obtained from resting-state fMRI by using intrinsic connectivity contrast (ICC), a voxel-based network measure of degree that reflects the number of connections to each voxel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioImage Suite: An integrated medical image analysis suite: An update</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-11-04_insight-j_136/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-11-04_insight-j_136/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiofrequency pulse design using nonlinear gradient magnetic fields</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-09-10_magn-reson-med_132/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-09-10_magn-reson-med_132/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: An iterative k-space trajectory and radiofrequency (RF) pulse design method is proposed for excitation using nonlinear gradient magnetic fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leptin is associated with exaggerated brain reward and emotion responses to food images in adolescent obesity</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-08-21_diabetes-care_160/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-08-21_diabetes-care_160/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: In the U.S., an astonishing 12.5 million children and adolescents are now obese, predisposing 17% of our nation&amp;rsquo;s youth to metabolic complications of obesity, such as type 2 diabetes (T2D).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo-random center placement O-space imaging for improved incoherence compressed sensing parallel MRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-07-22_magn-reson-med_219/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-07-22_magn-reson-med_219/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GABA, resting-state connectivity and the developing brain</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-06-28_neonatology_77/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-06-28_neonatology_77/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Preclinical data demonstrate that gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA) interneurons initiate connectivity in the developing brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOLD signal and functional connectivity associated with loving kindness meditation</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-06-20_brain-behav_104/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-06-20_brain-behav_104/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Loving kindness is a form of meditation involving directed well-wishing, typically supported by the silent repetition of phrases such as &amp;ldquo;may all beings be happy,&amp;rdquo; to foster a feeling of selfless love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algebraic reconstruction technique for parallel imaging reconstruction of undersampled radial data: application to cardiac cine</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-04-23_magn-reson-med_138/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-04-23_magn-reson-med_138/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: To investigate algebraic reconstruction technique (ART) for parallel imaging reconstruction of radial data, applied to accelerated cardiac cine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered brain connectivity in sagittal craniosynostosis</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-04-22_j-neurosurg-pediatr_67/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-04-22_j-neurosurg-pediatr_67/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECT: Sagittal nonsyndromic craniosynostosis (sNSC) is the most common form of NSC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coupled Intrinsic Connectivity Distribution analysis: a method for exploratory connectivity analysis of paired FMRI data</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-03-29_plos-one_139/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-03-29_plos-one_139/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a novel voxel-based connectivity approach for paired functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) data collected under two different conditions labeled the Coupled Intrinsic Connectivity Distribution (coupled-ICD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of image smoothness on intrinsic functional connectivity and head motion confounds</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-03-25_neuroimage_125/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-03-25_neuroimage_125/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a novel method for controlling the effects of group differences in motion on functional connectivity studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modulating intrinsic connectivity: adjacent subregions within supplementary motor cortex, dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, and parietal cortex connect to separate functional networks during task and also connect during rest</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-03-19_plos-one_209/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-03-19_plos-one_209/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional MRI signal fluctuations: a preclinical biomarker for cognitive impairment in type 2 diabetes?</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-01-28_diabetes_102/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-01-28_diabetes_102/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single echo MRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-01-28_plos-one_26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-01-28_plos-one_26/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Publisher: La mesure par IRMf (imagerie par résonance magnétique fonctionnelle) de la connectivité fonctionnelle cérébrale est une technique courante d&amp;rsquo;observation de l&amp;rsquo;organisation neurologique chez les sujets sains et les sujets souffrant de maladie mentale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiecho acquisition of O-space data</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-01-25_magn-reson-med_99/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-01-25_magn-reson-med_99/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: Nonlinear gradient encoding methods, such as O-Space imaging, have been shown to provide good images from very few echoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebral Lateralization is Protective in the Very Prematurely Born</title>
      <link>/publications/2014-01-24_cereb-cortex_65/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2014-01-24_cereb-cortex_65/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Individuals born prematurely are at risk for developmental delay, and converging data suggest alterations in neural networks in the developing preterm brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A preliminary investigation of Stroop-related intrinsic connectivity in cocaine dependence: associations with treatment outcomes</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-11-09_am-j-drug-alcohol-abuse_142/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-11-09_am-j-drug-alcohol-abuse_142/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninvasive MRI measurement of the absolute cerebral blood volume-cerebral blood flow relationship during visual stimulation in healthy humans</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-10-24_magn-reson-med_170/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-10-24_magn-reson-med_170/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: The relationship between cerebral blood volume (CBV) and cerebral blood flow (CBF) underlies blood oxygenation level-dependent functional MRI signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disruption of functional networks in dyslexia: a whole-brain, data-driven analysis of connectivity</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-10-16_biol-psychiatry_130/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-10-16_biol-psychiatry_130/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Functional connectivity analyses of functional magnetic resonance imaging data are a powerful tool for characterizing brain networks and how they are disrupted in neural disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of neuroanatomical measurements in a multisite longitudinal study of youth at risk for psychosis</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-08-29_hum-brain-mapp_131/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-08-29_hum-brain-mapp_131/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Multisite longitudinal neuroimaging designs are used to identify differential brain structural change associated with onset or progression of disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A feasibility study of magnetic resonance driven electrical impedance tomography using a phantom</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-05-31_physiol-meas_252/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-05-31_physiol-meas_252/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time fMRI links subjective experience with brain activity during focused attention</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-05-21_neuroimage_126/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-05-21_neuroimage_126/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent advances in brain imaging have improved the measure of neural processes related to perceptual, cognitive and affective functions, yet the relation between brain activity and subjective experience remains poorly characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupted ventromedial prefrontal function, alcohol craving, and subsequent relapse risk</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-05-03_jama-psychiatry_108/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-05-03_jama-psychiatry_108/</guid>
      <description>Abstract IMPORTANCE: Alcohol dependence is a chronic relapsing illness; stress, alcohol-related cues, and neutral-relaxing states significantly influence craving and relapse risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A graphics processing unit accelerated motion correction algorithm and modular system for real-time fMRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-01-16_neuroinformatics_236/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-01-16_neuroinformatics_236/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of fructose vs glucose on regional cerebral blood flow in brain regions involved with appetite and reward pathways</title>
      <link>/publications/2013-01-03_jama_207/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2013-01-03_jama_207/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A left cerebellar pathway mediates language in prematurely-born young adults</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-09-18_neuroimage_114/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-09-18_neuroimage_114/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Sequences that encode the spatial information of an object using nonlinear gradient fields are a new frontier in MRI, with potential to provide lower peripheral nerve stimulation, windowed fields of view, tailored spatially-varying resolution, curved slices that mirror physiological geometry, and, most importantly, very fast parallel imaging with multichannel coils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic brain connectivity related to age in young and middle aged adults</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-09-18_plos-one_117/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-09-18_plos-one_117/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Age-related variations in resting state connectivity of the human brain were examined from young adulthood through middle age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does baseline cerebral blood flow affect task-related blood oxygenation level dependent response in schizophrenia?</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-07-14_schizophr-res_149/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-07-14_schizophr-res_149/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Experimental changes in resting cerebral blood flow (CBF) affect task-related blood oxygenation level dependent (BOLD) responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ipsilateral synkinesia involves the supplementary motor area</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-07-05_neurosci-lett_75/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-07-05_neurosci-lett_75/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The supplementary motor area coordinates movements. Synkinesia is a rare disorder in which an involuntary movement occurs coordinated with a voluntary movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variants in the DYX2 locus are associated with altered brain activation in reading-related brain regions in subjects with reading disability</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-07-04_neuroimage_222/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-07-04_neuroimage_222/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo O-Space imaging with a dedicated 12 cm Z2 insert coil on a human 3T scanner using phase map calibration</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-05-16_magn-reson-med_245/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-05-16_magn-reson-med_245/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between phonological and auditory processing and brain organization in beginning readers</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-05-11_brain-lang_105/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-05-11_brain-lang_105/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We employed brain-behavior analyses to explore the relationship between performance on tasks measuring phonological awareness, pseudoword decoding, and rapid auditory processing (all predictors of reading (dis)ability) and brain organization for print and speech in beginning readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biofeedback of real-time functional magnetic resonance imaging data from the supplementary motor area reduces functional connectivity to subcortical regions</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-03-22_brain-connect_203/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-03-22_brain-connect_203/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time fMRI biofeedback targeting the orbitofrontal cortex for contamination anxiety</title>
      <link>/publications/2012-02-03_j-vis-exp_127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2012-02-03_j-vis-exp_127/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a method for training subjects to control activity in a region of their orbitofrontal cortex associated with contamination anxiety using biofeedback of real-time functional magnetic resonance imaging (rt-fMRI) data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null space imaging: nonlinear magnetic encoding fields designed complementary to receiver coil sensitivities for improved acceleration in parallel imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-12-23_magn-reson-med_246/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-12-23_magn-reson-med_246/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altered age-related trajectories of amygdala-prefrontal circuitry in adolescents at clinical high risk for psychosis: a preliminary study</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-11-08_schizophr-res_173/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-11-08_schizophr-res_173/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Emotion processing deficits are prominent in schizophrenia and exist prior to the onset of overt psychosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lateral ventricle volume and psychotic features in adolescents and adults with bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-11-02_psychiatry-res_115/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-11-02_psychiatry-res_115/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOLD response to semantic and syntactic processing during hypoglycemia is load-dependent</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-10-18_brain-lang_122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-10-18_brain-lang_122/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This study investigates how syntactic and semantic load factors impact sentence comprehension and BOLD signal under moderate hypoglycemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time course of regional brain activity accompanying auditory verbal hallucinations in schizophrenia</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-10-06_br-j-psychiatry_147/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-10-06_br-j-psychiatry_147/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: The pathophysiology of auditory verbal hallucinations remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulating glucose levels modulate neural control of desire for high-calorie foods in humans</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-09-20_j-clin-invest_151/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-09-20_j-clin-invest_151/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Obesity is a worldwide epidemic resulting in part from the ubiquity of high-calorie foods and food images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissociation between the activity of the right middle frontal gyrus and the middle temporal gyrus in processing semantic priming</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-08-11_plos-one_208/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-08-11_plos-one_208/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional MRI connectivity as a predictor of the surgical outcome of epilepsy</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-08-02_epilepsia_135/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-08-02_epilepsia_135/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BioImage Suite is an NIH-supported medical image analysis software suite developed at Yale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A whole-brain voxel based measure of intrinsic connectivity contrast reveals local changes in tissue connectivity with anesthetic without a priori assumptions on thresholds or regions of interest</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-07-19_neuroimage_228/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-07-19_neuroimage_228/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin dephasing under nonlinear gradients: implications for imaging and field mapping</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-07-16_magn-reson-med_253/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-07-16_magn-reson-med_253/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social network theory applied to resting-state fMRI connectivity data in the identification of epilepsy networks with iterative feature selection</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-05-17_j-neurosci-methods_215/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-05-17_j-neurosci-methods_215/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced genual corpus callosal white matter integrity in pathological gambling and its relationship to alcohol abuse or dependence</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-05-07_world-j-biol-psychiatry_213/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-05-07_world-j-biol-psychiatry_213/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impaired attention and network connectivity in childhood absence epilepsy</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-03-23_neuroimage_106/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-03-23_neuroimage_106/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Patients with childhood absence epilepsy (CAE) often demonstrate impaired interictal attention, even with control of their seizures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microstructural and functional connectivity in the developing preterm brain</title>
      <link>/publications/2011-01-25_semin-perinatol_86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2011-01-25_semin-perinatol_86/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Prematurely born children are at increased risk for cognitive deficits, but the neurobiological basis of these findings remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic resonance driven electrical impedance tomography: a simulation study</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-12-15_ieee-trans-med-imaging_248/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-12-15_ieee-trans-med-imaging_248/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preterm birth results in alterations in neural connectivity at age 16 years</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-11-16_neuroimage_146/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-11-16_neuroimage_146/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Very low birth weight preterm (PT) children are at high risk for brain injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O-space imaging: Highly efficient parallel imaging using second-order nonlinear fields as encoding gradients with no phase encoding</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-07-29_magn-reson-med_202/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-07-29_magn-reson-med_202/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity between task-positive and task-negative brain areas and its relation to working memory performance</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-04-23_magn-reson-imaging_162/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-04-23_magn-reson-imaging_162/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional brain imaging studies have identified a set of brain areas typically activated during cognitive tasks (task-positive brain areas) and another set of brain areas typically deactivated during cognitive tasks (task-negative brain areas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity to a right hemisphere language center in prematurely born adolescents</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-03-30_neuroimage_158/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-03-30_neuroimage_158/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Prematurely born children are at increased risk for language deficits at school age and beyond, but the neurobiological basis of these findings remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unification of sentence processing via ear and eye: an fMRI study</title>
      <link>/publications/2010-02-02_cortex_144/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2010-02-02_cortex_144/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present new evidence based on fMRI for the existence and neural architecture of an abstract supramodal language system that can integrate linguistic inputs arising from different modalities such that speech and print each activate a common code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surgically implantable magnetic resonance angiography coils improve resolution to allow visualization of blood flow dynamics</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-12-29_ann-vasc-surg_169/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-12-29_ann-vasc-surg_169/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Magnetic resonance angiography (MRA) is clinically useful but of limited applicability to small animal models due to poor signal resolution, with typical voxel sizes of 1 mm(3) that are insufficient to analyze vessels of diameter &amp;lt;1 mm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arterial transit time effects in pulsed arterial spin labeling CBF mapping: insight from a PET and MR study in normal human subjects</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-12-03_magn-reson-med_225/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-12-03_magn-reson-med_225/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexually dimorphic features of vermis morphology in bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-10-21_bipolar-disord_134/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-10-21_bipolar-disord_134/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVES: The cerebellar vermis is increasingly implicated in bipolar disorder (BD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity and alterations in baseline brain state in humans</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-07-28_neuroimage_133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-07-28_neuroimage_133/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This work examines the influence of changes in baseline activity on the intrinsic functional connectivity fMRI (fc-fMRI) in humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similar and dissociable mechanisms for attention to internal versus external information</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-07-15_neuroimage_171/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-07-15_neuroimage_171/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We compared two attentional executive processes: updating, which involved attending to a perceptually present stimulus, and refreshing, which involved attending to a mentally active representation of a stimulus no longer perceptually present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alterations in neural connectivity in preterm children at school age</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-06-30_neuroimage_150/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-06-30_neuroimage_150/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Converging data suggest recovery from injury in the preterm brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language lateralization in epilepsy patients: fMRI validated with the Wada procedure</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-06-04_epilepsia_163/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-06-04_epilepsia_163/</guid>
      <description>Abstract PURPOSE: This work examines the efficacy of functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) for language lateralization using a comprehensive three-task language-mapping approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of SLC6A3 and COMT variation on neural activation during response inhibition</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-06-02_biol-psychol_237/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-06-02_biol-psychol_237/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relation between amygdala structure and function in adolescents with bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-05-21_j-am-acad-child-adolesc-psychiatry_167/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-05-21_j-am-acad-child-adolesc-psychiatry_167/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glucose dysregulation and hepatic steatosis in obese adolescents: is there a link?</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-05-13_hepatology_161/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-05-13_hepatology_161/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Fatty liver is increasingly common in obese adolescents. We determined its association with glucose dysregulation in 118 (37M/81F) obese adolescents of similar age and percent total fat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional and structural connectivity between the perigenual anterior cingulate and amygdala in bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-05-12_biol-psychiatry_185/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-05-12_biol-psychiatry_185/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: Abnormalities in the morphology and function of two gray matter structures central to emotional processing, the perigenual anterior cingulate cortex (pACC) and amygdala, have consistently been reported in bipolar disorder (BD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary evidence for progressive prefrontal abnormalities in adolescents and young adults with bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-05-01_j-int-neuropsychol-soc_172/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-05-01_j-int-neuropsychol-soc_172/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Previous cross-sectional study of ventral prefrontal cortex (VPFC) implicated progressive volume abnormalities during adolescence in bipolar disorder (BD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variation in language networks in monolingual and bilingual English speakers: consequences for language mapping for surgical preplanning</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-04-17_j-clin-exp-neuropsychol_211/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-04-17_j-clin-exp-neuropsychol_211/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonological awareness predicts activation patterns for print and speech</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-03-24_ann-dyslexia_129/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-03-24_ann-dyslexia_129/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Using fMRI, we explored the relationship between phonological awareness (PA), a measure of metaphonological knowledge of the segmental structure of speech, and brain activation patterns during processing of print and speech in young readers from 6 to 10 years of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of hepatic fibrosis with portal pressure gradient in rats</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-03-03_magn-reson-med_145/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-03-03_magn-reson-med_145/</guid>
      <description>Abstract MRI has the potential of providing a noninvasive assessment of liver pathology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of functional connectivity with the syntactic and semantic demands of a Noun Phrase Formation Task: a possible role for the Default Network</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-02-25_neuroimage_234/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-02-25_neuroimage_234/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal brain volume changes in preterm and term control subjects during late childhood and adolescence</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-01-28_pediatrics_193/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-01-28_pediatrics_193/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: Although preterm very low birth weight infants have a high prevalence of neuroanatomical abnormalities when evaluated at term-equivalent age, patterns of brain growth in prematurely born infants during school age and adolescence remain largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alterations in functional connectivity for language in prematurely born adolescents</title>
      <link>/publications/2009-01-23_brain_154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2009-01-23_brain_154/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent data suggest recovery of language systems but persistent structural abnormalities in the prematurely born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain areas coactivating with motor cortex during chronic motor tics and intentional movements</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-12-30_biol-psychiatry_180/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-12-30_biol-psychiatry_180/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Chronic tic disorders are characterized by motor tics that are often preceded by premonitory urges to tic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of variation in the serotonin transporter protein gene (SLC6A4) in trait disturbances in the ventral anterior cingulate in bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-11-28_neuropsychopharmacology_231/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-11-28_neuropsychopharmacology_231/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small decrements in systemic glucose provoke increases in hypothalamic blood flow prior to the release of counterregulatory hormones</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-11-20_diabetes_214/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-11-20_diabetes_214/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparator and non-comparator mechanisms of change detection in the context of speech--an ERP study</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-10-22_neuroimage_254/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-10-22_neuroimage_254/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impairment of working memory maintenance and response in schizophrenia: functional magnetic resonance imaging evidence</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-10-01_biol-psychiatry_188/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-10-01_biol-psychiatry_188/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transverse patterning dissociates human EEG theta power and hippocampal BOLD activation</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-10-01_psychophysiology_148/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-10-01_psychophysiology_148/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Theta oscillations (4-8 Hz) are often modulated in human electroencephalogram (EEG) studies of memory, whereas overlapping frequencies dominate rodent hippocampal EEG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anesthetic effects on regional CBF, BOLD, and the coupling between task-induced changes in CBF and BOLD: an fMRI study in normal human subjects</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-09-26_magn-reson-med_233/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-09-26_magn-reson-med_233/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal brain response to own baby-cry is affected by cesarean section delivery</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-09-06_j-child-psychol-psychiatry_191/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-09-06_j-child-psychol-psychiatry_191/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abnormal anterior cingulum integrity in bipolar disorder determined through diffusion tensor imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-08-02_br-j-psychiatry_176/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-08-02_br-j-psychiatry_176/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Convergent evidence implicates white matter abnormalities in bipolar disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity with the anterior cingulate is associated with extraversion during the emotional Stroop task</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-07-18_soc-neurosci_184/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-07-18_soc-neurosci_184/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Previous research has investigated the association of personality traits with brain activation in response to emotional stimuli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional magnetic resonance imaging of temporally distinct responses to emotional facial expressions</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-07-18_soc-neurosci_181/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-07-18_soc-neurosci_181/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Understanding the temporal dynamics of brain function contributes to models of learning and memory as well as the processing of emotions and habituation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abnormal corpus callosum integrity in bipolar disorder: a diffusion tensor imaging study</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-07-16_biol-psychiatry_166/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-07-16_biol-psychiatry_166/</guid>
      <description>Abstract OBJECTIVE: Previous study supports the presence of reduced volume and elevated response to emotional stimuli in amygdala in adolescents with bipolar disorder (BD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More accurate Talairach coordinates for neuroimaging using non-linear registration</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-06-24_neuroimage_121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-06-24_neuroimage_121/</guid>
      <description>Abstract While the Talairach atlas remains the most commonly used system for reporting coordinates in neuroimaging studies, the absence of an actual 3-D image of the original brain used in its construction has severely limited the ability of researchers to automatically map locations from 3-D anatomical MRI images to the atlas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop the sadness: Neuroticism is associated with sustained medial prefrontal cortex response to emotional facial expressions</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-05-31_neuroimage_189/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-05-31_neuroimage_189/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Neuroticism is a personality trait associated with negative mood states, sensitivity to negative information, negative appraisal and vulnerability to psychopathology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induced hepatic fibrosis in rats: hepatic steatosis, macromolecule content, perfusion parameters, and their correlations--preliminary MR imaging in rats</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-04-12_radiology_220/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-04-12_radiology_220/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain volume reductions within multiple cognitive systems in male preterm children at age twelve</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-03-19_j-pediatr_187/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-03-19_j-pediatr_187/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Comparing prefrontal cortical activity during particular phases of working memory in healthy subjects and individuals diagnosed with schizophrenia might help to define the phase-specific deficits in cortical function that contribute to cognitive impairments associated with schizophrenia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additive effects of serotonin transporter and tryptophan hydroxylase-2 gene variation on neural correlates of affective processing</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-03-04_biol-psychol_183/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-03-04_biol-psychol_183/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Individual differences in brain response to emotional stimuli have previously been associated with gene variations within the serotonin transporter (5-HTT) and tryptophan hydroxylase-2 (TPH2) genes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative MR study of hepatic fat quantification using single-voxel proton spectroscopy, two-point dixon and three-point IDEAL</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-02-29_magn-reson-med_197/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-02-29_magn-reson-med_197/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Hepatic fat fraction (HFF) was measured in 28 lean/obese humans by single-voxel proton spectroscopy (MRS), a two-point Dixon (2PD), and a three-point iterative decomposition of water and fat with echo asymmetry and least-squares estimation (IDEAL) method (3PI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting change in BOLD signal between sessions for atlas-based anatomical ROIs</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-02-26_neuroimage_242/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-02-26_neuroimage_242/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of stimulus difficulty and repetition on printed word identification: an fMRI comparison of nonimpaired and reading-disabled adolescent cohorts</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-02-21_j-cogn-neurosci_182/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-02-21_j-cogn-neurosci_182/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional neuroimaging studies indicate that a primary marker of specific reading disability (RD) is reduced activation of left hemisphere (LH) posterior regions during performance of reading tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prematurely born children demonstrate white matter microstructural differences at 12 years of age, relative to term control subjects: an investigation of group and gender effects</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-02-05_pediatrics_235/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-02-05_pediatrics_235/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensory and cognitive mechanisms of change detection in the context of speech</title>
      <link>/publications/2008-01-15_brain-struct-funct_159/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2008-01-15_brain-struct-funct_159/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The aim of this study was to dissociate the contributions of memory-based (cognitive) and adaptation-based (sensory) mechanisms underlying deviance detection in the context of natural speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of working memory load on oscillatory power in human intracranial EEG</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-12-07_cereb-cortex_177/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-12-07_cereb-cortex_177/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Studies of working memory load effects on human EEG power have indicated divergent effects in different frequency bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic imaging of lymphatic vessels and lymph nodes using a bimodal nanoparticulate contrast agent</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-11-27_lymphat-res-biol_194/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-11-27_lymphat-res-biol_194/</guid>
      <description>Abstract BACKGROUND: Evaluation of lymphedema and lymph node metastasis in humans has relied primarily on invasive or radioactive modalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injury and recovery in the developing brain: evidence from functional MRI studies of prematurely born children</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-10-05_nat-clin-pract-neurol_40/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-10-05_nat-clin-pract-neurol_40/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Functional MRI (fMRI) might provide important insights into emerging data that suggest that recovery from injury can occur in the brains of children born prematurely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual differences in EEG theta and alpha dynamics during working memory correlate with fMRI responses across subjects</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-09-29_clin-neurophysiol_205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-09-29_clin-neurophysiol_205/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the radio frequency pulse artifact in simultaneous EEG-fMRI recording: rectification at the carbon-metal interface</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-09-18_ieee-trans-biomed-eng_241/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-09-18_ieee-trans-biomed-eng_241/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the application of chemical shift-based multipoint water-fat separation methods in balanced SSFP imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-07-27_magn-reson-med_244/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-07-27_magn-reson-med_244/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acupuncture-induced blood oxygenation level-dependent signals in awake and anesthetized volunteers: a pilot study</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-07-25_anesth-analg_178/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-07-25_anesth-analg_178/</guid>
      <description>Abstract RATIONALE: Efficient function of neurocircuitry that supports working memory occurs within a narrow range of dopamine neurotransmission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanosystems for simultaneous imaging and drug delivery to T cells</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-07-07_aaps-j_38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-07-07_aaps-j_38/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Sophisticated neuroimaging strategies demonstrate alterations in functional connectivity at school age, adolescence, and young adulthood in individuals born preterm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of smoking abstinence on working memory neurocircuitry in adolescent daily tobacco smokers</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-05-17_psychopharmacology-berl_179/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-05-17_psychopharmacology-berl_179/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to detect taste in a tasteless solution: modulation of early gustatory cortex by attention to taste</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-05-15_chem-senses_165/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-05-15_chem-senses_165/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Selective attention is thought to be associated with enhanced processing in modality-specific cortex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional conflict and neuroticism: personality-dependent activation in the amygdala and subgenual anterior cingulate</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-05-02_behav-neurosci_168/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-05-02_behav-neurosci_168/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The amygdala and subgenual anterior cingulate (AC) have been associated with anxiety and mood disorders, for which trait neuroticism is a risk factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biphasic hemodynamic responses influence deactivation and may mask activation in block-design fMRI paradigms</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-04-24_hum-brain-mapp_198/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-04-24_hum-brain-mapp_198/</guid>
      <description>Abstract A previous block-design fMRI study revealed deactivation in the hippocampus in the transverse patterning task, specifically designed, on the basis of lesion literature, to engage hippocampal information processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age-related changes in reading systems of dyslexic children</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-04-21_ann-neurol_112/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-04-21_ann-neurol_112/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Meditation has been associated with relatively reduced activity in the default mode network, a brain network implicated in self-related thinking and mind wandering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is automatic emotion regulation associated with agreeableness? A perspective using a social neuroscience approach</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-04-12_psychol-sci_143/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-04-12_psychol-sci_143/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probing the pathophysiology of auditory/verbal hallucinations by combining functional magnetic resonance imaging and transcranial magnetic stimulation</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-02-15_cereb-cortex_206/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-02-15_cereb-cortex_206/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain tissue segmentation based on corrected gray-scale analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/2007-02-07_conf-proc-ieee-eng-med-biol-soc_249/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2007-02-07_conf-proc-ieee-eng-med-biol-soc_249/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain connectivity related to working memory performance</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-12-22_j-neurosci_118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-12-22_j-neurosci_118/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Several brain areas show signal decreases during many different cognitive tasks in functional imaging studies, including the posterior cingulate cortex (PCC) and a medial frontal region incorporating portions of the medial frontal gyrus and ventral anterior cingulate cortex (MFG/vACC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural correlates of epigenesis</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-10-13_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_49/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-10-13_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_49/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hemodynamic retrieval intensity in hippocampus is decreased by pre-exposure to autobiographic test items</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-10-10_brain-res-bull_196/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-10-10_brain-res-bull_196/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cortical recruitment patterns in children born prematurely compared with control subjects during a passive listening functional magnetic resonance imaging task</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-10-03_j-pediatr_232/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-10-03_j-pediatr_232/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interference produced by emotional conflict associated with anterior cingulate activation</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-09-30_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_156/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-09-30_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_156/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The anterior cingulate cortex (ACC) is involved in cognition and emotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A functional magnetic resonance imaging study of the long-term influences of early indomethacin exposure on language processing in the brains of prematurely born children</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-09-05_pediatrics_230/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-09-05_pediatrics_230/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alanine aminotransferase levels and fatty liver in childhood obesity: associations with insulin resistance, adiponectin, and visceral fat</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-08-17_j-clin-endocrinol-metab_217/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-08-17_j-clin-endocrinol-metab_217/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T1 measurements incorporating flip angle calibration and correction in vivo</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-08-01_j-magn-reson_239/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-08-01_j-magn-reson_239/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender differences in the neural correlates of response inhibition during a stop signal task</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-06-30_neuroimage_192/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-06-30_neuroimage_192/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We used functional magnetic resonance imaging to examine gender differences in the neural correlates of response inhibition during a stop signal task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors influencing flip angle mapping in MRI: RF pulse shape, slice-select gradients, off-resonance excitation, and B0 inhomogeneities</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-06-15_magn-reson-med_243/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-06-15_magn-reson-med_243/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of estrogen variation on neural correlates of emotional response inhibition</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-04-29_neuroimage_152/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-04-29_neuroimage_152/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Conflict of interest statement: In the interest of full disclosure, DG is founder and chief scientific and strategy advisor at Salimetrics LLC and Salivabio LLC (Carlsbad, CA) and these relationships are managed by the policies of the committee’s on conflict of interest at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine and the University of California at Irvine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connectivity-behavior analysis reveals that functional connectivity between left BA39 and Broca&#39;s area varies with reading ability</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-02-25_neuroimage_175/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-02-25_neuroimage_175/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Correlations between temporal fluctuations in MRI signals may reveal functional connectivity between brain regions within individual subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence that autobiographic memory retrieval does not become independent of the hippocampus: an fMRI study contrasting very recent with remote events</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-02-16_j-cogn-neurosci_221/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-02-16_j-cogn-neurosci_221/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differentiation of speech and nonspeech processing within primary auditory cortex</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-02-04_j-acoust-soc-am_155/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-02-04_j-acoust-soc-am_155/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Primary auditory cortex (PAC), located in Heschl&amp;rsquo;s gyrus (HG), is the earliest cortical level at which sounds are processed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging response inhibition in a stop-signal task: neural correlates independent of signal monitoring and post-response processing</title>
      <link>/publications/2006-01-10_j-neurosci_204/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2006-01-10_j-neurosci_204/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent cannabis abuse decreased stress-induced BOLD signals in the frontal and cingulate cortices of cocaine dependent individuals</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-11-18_psychiatry-res_218/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-11-18_psychiatry-res_218/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amygdala gray matter concentration is associated with extraversion and neuroticism</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-11-08_neuroreport_128/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-11-08_neuroreport_128/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Using high-resolution magnetic resonance imaging and voxel-based morphometry in 41 healthy individuals, this study evaluated the association between the personality traits of extraversion and neuroticism, on the one hand, and individual differences in localized brain volume and gray matter concentration, on the other, with a special focus on the amygdala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fMRI hippocampal activity during a virtual radial arm maze</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-09-17_appl-psychophysiol-biofeedback_141/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-09-17_appl-psychophysiol-biofeedback_141/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond affect: a role for genetic variation of the serotonin transporter in neural activation during a cognitive attention task</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-08-12_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_247/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-08-12_proc-natl-acad-sci-u-s-a_247/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White matter tractography by anisotropic wavefront evolution and diffusion tensor imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-07-26_med-image-anal_195/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-07-26_med-image-anal_195/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The purpose of this experiment was to assess the effects of probe familiarity, the consequences of having recently retrieved an autobiographic memory (AM), on subsequent recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo method for correcting transmit/receive nonuniformities with phased array coils</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-02-22_magn-reson-med_240/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-02-22_magn-reson-med_240/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement and correction of transmitter and receiver induced nonuniformities in vivo</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-01-29_magn-reson-med_174/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-01-29_magn-reson-med_174/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Signal intensity nonuniformities in high field MR imaging limit the ability of MRI to provide quantitative information and can negatively impact diagnostic scan quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activation of human hippocampal formation reflects success in both encoding and cued recall of paired associates</title>
      <link>/publications/2005-01-04_neuroimage_210/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2005-01-04_neuroimage_210/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear estimation and modeling of fMRI data using spatio-temporal support vector regression</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-09-04_inf-process-med-imaging_190/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-09-04_inf-process-med-imaging_190/</guid>
      <description>Abstract A range of early circumstances surrounding the birth of a child affects peripartum hormones, parental behavior and infant wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hippocampal dampening during a relational memory task</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-08-11_behav-neurosci_251/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-08-11_behav-neurosci_251/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The neurobiology of adaptive learning in reading: a contrast of different training conditions</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-07-21_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_199/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-07-21_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_199/</guid>
      <description>Abstract fMRI was used to investigate the separate influences of orthographic, phonological, and semantic processing on the ability to learn new words and the cortical circuitry recruited to subsequently read those words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The neurobiology of adaptive learning in reading: a contrast of different training conditions</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-07-21_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_200/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-07-21_cogn-affect-behav-neurosci_200/</guid>
      <description>Abstract fMRI was used to investigate the separate influences of orthographic, phonological, and semantic processing on the ability to learn new words and the cortical circuitry recruited to subsequently read those words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of left occipitotemporal systems for skilled reading in children after a phonologically- based intervention</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-04-28_biol-psychiatry_216/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-04-28_biol-psychiatry_216/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentence complexity and input modality effects in sentence comprehension: an fMRI study</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-04-28_neuroimage_201/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-04-28_neuroimage_201/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex differences and correlations in a virtual Morris water task, a virtual radial arm maze, and mental rotation</title>
      <link>/publications/2004-04-16_behav-brain-res_229/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2004-04-16_behav-brain-res_229/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural systems for compensation and persistence: young adult outcome of childhood reading disability</title>
      <link>/publications/2003-07-05_biol-psychiatry_212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2003-07-05_biol-psychiatry_212/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MR physics of body MR imaging</title>
      <link>/publications/2003-03-13_radiol-clin-north-am_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2003-03-13_radiol-clin-north-am_17/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of 3-D left ventricular deformation from medical images using biomechanical models</title>
      <link>/publications/2002-10-11_ieee-trans-med-imaging_224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2002-10-11_ieee-trans-med-imaging_224/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disruption of posterior brain systems for reading in children with developmental dyslexia</title>
      <link>/publications/2002-07-13_biol-psychiatry_223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2002-07-13_biol-psychiatry_223/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image distortion correction in EPI: comparison of field mapping with point spread function mapping</title>
      <link>/publications/2002-07-12_magn-reson-med_227/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2002-07-12_magn-reson-med_227/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-invasive assessment of language lateralization by transcranial near infrared optical topography and functional MRI</title>
      <link>/publications/2002-07-12_hum-brain-mapp_226/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2002-07-12_hum-brain-mapp_226/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To be imported ..</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>